Sometimes finding the truth is easier than facing it.
In the Valley of Elah is a history, drama,
thriller film directed by Paul Haggis.
A career officer and his wife work with a police detective to uncover the truth behind
their son's disappearance following his return from a tour of duty in Iraq.
Hank Deerfield, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Detective Emily Sanders, played by Charlize Theron.
Joan Deerfield, played by Susan Sarandon.
Evie, played by Frances Fisher.
Sergeant Carnelli, played by James Franco.
Mike Deerfield, played by Jonathan Tucker.
In the Valley of Elah is a 2007 American crime drama
film written and directed by Paul Haggis.
The film stars Tommy Lee Jones, Charlize Theron, and Susan Sarandon.
Its title refers to the Biblical valley where the battle
between David and Goliath took place.
The film is based on actual events, although the
characters' names and locations have been changed.
The screenplay was inspired by journalist Mark Boal's "Death and Dishonor", an
article about the murder case published in Playboy magazine in 2004.
It portrays a military father's search for his son and, after his
body is found, subsequent hunt for his son's killers.
The film explores themes including the Iraq War, abuse of
prisoners, and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD).
The film explores themes of police, parent child
relationship, war crimes, homicide, detective.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.